[{"id": "5ff5151fff04d658268c92e7", "question": "What weapon was developed in 1942 in a secret laboratory at Harvard University?", "answer": "Napalm", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a28e", "question": "Which US band had a 1974 hit song with \"Billy Don't Be a Hero\"?", "answer": "Bo Donaldson and The Heywoods", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c8e", "question": "What Beatles song repeats the title in the lyrics forty-one times?", "answer": "Let It Be", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b8cf2f94b094db915830ae", "question": "The Bical grape originates from which European country?", "answer": "Portugal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339344", "question": "Who was the first winner of \"American Idol\"?", "answer": "Kelly Clarkson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339736", "question": "In the TV series \"Lost\", which airline's plane crashed?", "answer": "Oceanic Airlines", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597ddbc577980686f722d178", "question": "What year was the modern pencil sharpener invented?", "answer": "1847", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be4b", "question": "What two pins are left standing in bowling's hardest split to pick up?", "answer": "The 7 and 10", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59523e5b736d4be723796b4f", "question": "In what decade did Toronto surpass Montreal as the most populous city in Canada?", "answer": "1970s", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5e6", "question": "Which missionary was the first European to discover Victoria Falls?", "answer": "David Livingstone", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c074", "question": "What is the regulation height for a pin in Ten Pin bowling?", "answer": "Fifteen inches", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0af", "question": "Who recorded the album \"Beggars Banquet\"?", "answer": "Rolling Stones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a13e", "question": "What actress wrote the autobiography \"Call Me Anna\"?", "answer": "Patty Duke", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d470c8f8e329de4f877895", "question": "What war lasted from June 5 to June 10, 1967?", "answer": "Six-Day War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338933", "question": "What is the name of Beethoven's only opera?", "answer": "Fidelio", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c652", "question": "What sense is most closely linked to memory?", "answer": "Smell", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e76", "question": "What superteam includes Cosmic Boy, Saturn Girl and Lightning Boy?", "answer": "The Legion of Super-Heroes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fffa1c173838c5c8a417f1c", "question": "How much more blood does a pregnant woman's body contain?", "answer": "The amount can increase by as much as 50% or more.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b46d", "question": "Sir Edmund Hillary and Tenzing Norgay were the first people to do what?", "answer": "Reach Mount Everest", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b323675bf195a31e15d73bb", "question": "The song \"Seven Seas of Rhye\" was the first hit for which band?", "answer": "Queen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dc4", "question": "By including cannon fire in his play, Henry VIII, Shakespeare caused the 1613 fire that destroyed what building?", "answer": "The Globe Theatre", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e8a60e49a45431f553a9ccd", "question": "What movie had the highest rating on IMDb in 2019?", "answer": "The Shawshank Redemption", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb5ce75dad637d903c8820", "question": "What country is nicknamed \"the land of a thousand lakes\"?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339024", "question": "What year did the first \"Where's Waldo?\" illustrated book hit the shelves?", "answer": "1987", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe93cbd6bd93ce3a4e5f6ab", "question": "What discovery earned Wilhelm Rontgen the first Nobel Prize for Physics?", "answer": "X-rays", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8a1", "question": "From which language do the tennis terms \"love\" and \"deuce\" originate?", "answer": "French", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fedd8cb6ce05a3942286d74", "question": "Which NBA player has had a tattoo of the late Malcolm X on his left calf at least since 2012?", "answer": "Derrick Rose", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b93a", "question": "What type of athlete is also called a powder puff, tanker, catcher or knuckle duster?", "answer": "A boxer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dc2", "question": "What disease is Mitch Albom's professor dying of in his best-seller \"Tuesday with Morrie\"?", "answer": "Lou Gehrig's disease", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa3c83c73aa70ea0b70aec", "question": "Which country's capital contains another country within its borders?", "answer": "Italy (Vatican City, the world's smallest independent nation-state, is fully contained within the city of Rome, Italy's capital.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fb1bffff497e33de805791b", "question": "What can be found inside a baseball?", "answer": "Rubber or cork, and yarn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5990afefb72eedf883a8c70c", "question": "The Island of Bornholm is part of which country?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7ee", "question": "In the UK, what is called a \"courgette\"?", "answer": "A zucchini", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8a7", "question": "In what country is the historic city of Bam?", "answer": "Iran", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1c1", "question": "What nationality was writer, neurologist and psychiatrist Viktor E. Frankl?", "answer": "Austrian", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339222", "question": "As a child, what did Casper the Friendly Ghost die from?", "answer": "Pneumonia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b981", "question": "What used to be called the apple of love or love apple ?", "answer": "The tomato", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b529", "question": "What does the abbreviation WWW stand for?", "answer": "World Wide Web", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a308", "question": "Which character did Madeleine Martin play on the TV show \"Californication\"?", "answer": "Becca Moody", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecdcfaec223966ae8f88fb", "question": "In the film \"Goodfellas\", what airline is robbed?", "answer": "Lufthansa", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaf8", "question": "N'Djamena is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Chad", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae73", "question": "What started in 1849 when gold was discovered at Sutter's Mill?", "answer": "The California Gold Rush", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bea2", "question": "What magazine ran the famous cover of a very pregnant Demi Moore in the buff?", "answer": "Vanity Fair", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339577", "question": "What is Scrooge's first name?", "answer": "Ebenezer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ff5", "question": "Who was the first African American to host a TV show?", "answer": "Nat King Cole", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c49d", "question": "Self-rising flour contains what crucial ingredient?", "answer": "Baking powder", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c46a", "question": "What does the medical acronym PET stand for?", "answer": "Positron Emission Tomography", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339368", "question": "In the 1960 movie \"Psycho\", what actor plays the private detective?", "answer": "Martin Balsam", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abd7", "question": "The island country Cyprus, lies within what water body?", "answer": "Mediterranean Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5921fdf9a4edfd43a087adcb", "question": "Disney's 2013 film \"Frozen\" was inspired by which fairy tale?", "answer": "The Snow Queen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5901d9c4709c1c34536e6eac", "question": "In the 2008 movie \"Step Brothers\", what is the name of Huff and Doback's entertainment company?", "answer": "Prestige Worldwide", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f7161a9e54d890926f6de", "question": "What is the capital city of Paraguay?", "answer": "Asuncion", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5b8", "question": "Zion National Park is located in which US state?", "answer": "Utah", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd81f5cd0de9af39e9d4696", "question": "Who was the first U.S. president to be on the radio?", "answer": "Warring G. Harding", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58bb358fe368446ca7bd6854", "question": "What is an Affogato?", "answer": "Gelato, or ice cream, topped with hot espresso", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a467", "question": "What city is the capital of the US state of New Mexico?", "answer": "Santa Fe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab7e", "question": "Sierra Leone is located on which African coast?", "answer": "West", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60173c3444491cbd7c5a17a4", "question": "What collectively-named languages evolved from Vulgar Latin?", "answer": "Romance or romanic language -- The five most spoken romance languages are Spanish, French, Portuguese, Italian and Romanian.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c396", "question": "What other name are killer whales known by?", "answer": "Orcas", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338afe", "question": "Which character killed Richard Cory?", "answer": "Himself", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a57a", "question": "Coney Island is located on what island?", "answer": "Long Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fec8610ec223966ae8f880d", "question": "What weapon was so powerful that Epic Games pulled it from \"Fortnite\" after only four days in December 2018?", "answer": "Infinity Blade", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ea", "question": "Excluding vowels with macrons, how many letters are in the Hawaiian alphabet?", "answer": "Twelve", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a68a", "question": "Lake Winnipesaukee is the largest lake in which US state?", "answer": "New Hampshire", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5902a06bcad1ec93f27df76b", "question": "Which Bohemian city gave us the Pilsner?", "answer": "Pilsen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6583aae7e414034b5aeea", "question": "What were Carrot, Goat, and Onion in WWII?", "answer": "British explosives", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fd0", "question": "What is the real identity of Aquaman?", "answer": "Arthur Curry", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339110", "question": "In which play by Tennessee Williams would you encounter the character \"Big Daddy\"?", "answer": "Cat on a Hot Tin Roof", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f91", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in \"The Turning Point\"?", "answer": "Leslie Brown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe12d6be39efa6330e0fecc", "question": "Where were the world's largest pearls found?", "answer": "The Philippines", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b83e", "question": "What 2 articles of clothing are tokens in the standard Monopoly game?", "answer": "Shoe and Top Hat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a841", "question": "The ancient city of Troy was located in what is now what country?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133904d", "question": "Who wrote the opera \"La Traviata\"?", "answer": "Guiseppe Verdi", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abdc", "question": "Where were the 1960 Summer Olympics held?", "answer": "Rome, Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5da855641aec824685d88d01", "question": "The \"Curse of the Bambino\" was a popular superstition in which sport?", "answer": "Baseball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8f3d601dd7bf43be5e818", "question": "OSHA stands for what in the US?", "answer": "Occupational Safety and Health Administration", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1e6", "question": "Guitarist Dave Navarro was married for just over three years to which star of \"Baywatch\" and \"Singled Out\"?", "answer": "Carmen Electra", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66044a5bfecdd737e0832", "question": "What was the first pizza chain in the United States?", "answer": "Pizza Hut", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad67", "question": "The original Teamsters union was formed to protect who?", "answer": "Horse carriage drivers", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a67", "question": "Who wrote the children's book \"The Trumpet of the Swan\"?", "answer": "E.B. White", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bde9", "question": "Shechita is the method of producing meat that is what?", "answer": "Kosher", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba21", "question": "What is the name given to the Cricketer's Year book, where all cricketing laws and scores are reported?", "answer": "Wisdens Almanac", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b80f", "question": "What two snacks are mentioned in \"Take Me Out to the Ballgame\"?", "answer": "Peanuts and Cracker Jack", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600b87561d8c1817608d53e8", "question": "Why does cheddar cheese need a bandage?", "answer": "It\u2019s aged longer -- Instead of wax, a bandage made of cloth is used to help the cheese \"breathe\" while it's in long-term storage.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b23b", "question": "What royal subject married Sarah Ferguson?", "answer": "Prince Andrew", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600241d94be4723ccac2217e", "question": "In the book \"The Hunt for Red October,\" how is the Soviet submarine V. K. Konovalov destroyed?", "answer": "Reactor meltdown", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca6e", "question": "Oak trees are part of which genus?", "answer": "Quercus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c119", "question": "A flag flown upside-down is a signal of what?", "answer": "Distress", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60121ac063c99d48cd169b07", "question": "Where was the world\u2019s first speeding ticket issued?", "answer": "England", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a86", "question": "What poet coined the phrase \"candy is dandy, but liquor is quicker\"?", "answer": "Ogden Nash", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a13", "question": "What was Ralph Kramden's weekly salary as a bus driver on \"The Honeymooners\"?", "answer": "$62", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede4ae6ce05a3942286de0", "question": "In which 2001 movie did Tim Roth play the character General Thade?", "answer": "\"Planet of the Apes\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e94d2015ea27d7a1303aed7", "question": "In what US state is the Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame located?", "answer": "Massachusetts", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59523ec4736d4be723796b53", "question": "What three provinces requested a single Dominion be formed in 1867, thus beginning to shape modern Canada?", "answer": "New Brunswick, Nova Scotia and the Province of Canada", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f2", "question": "What note is the highest string of a violin usually tuned to?", "answer": "E", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef59a56ce05a3942286e05", "question": "Walnut Grove, Minnesota is the setting for which television series?", "answer": "\"Little House on the Prairie\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb0e", "question": "What is the more common name for an Apiarist?", "answer": "Beekeeper", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b764", "question": "The name \"Chandler\" literally means what?", "answer": "Candlemaker", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a205", "question": "Who is Yogi Bear's sidekick?", "answer": "Boo Boo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a520", "question": "NATO's headquarters are located in which city?", "answer": "Brussels", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e70", "question": "What fictional village sits in the shadow of Mount Crumpit?", "answer": "Whoville", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a162a8df01ec323f8491724", "question": "For what did Christine Jorgensen became famous in 1952?", "answer": "The first widely known person in the US to undergo a sex change operation", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f42", "question": "Who created the character of Yogi Bear?", "answer": "William Hanna and Joseph Barbera", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6007815fbd51d85e222ab64b", "question": "What art movement employs aspects of mass culture, such as advertising, comic books and mundane cultural objects?", "answer": "Seeking to elevate popular culture to the level of fine art,\u00a0Pop artists\u00a0celebrated commonplace objects and everyday people.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59cdb46565ff7d326b622a87", "question": "What is the fear of glass known as?", "answer": "Nelophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5f9", "question": "What US city is nicknamed \"Beantown\"?", "answer": "Boston", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe3783c0ada16518afdc050", "question": "What was the first Christmas song to focus on Santa Claus?", "answer": "\"Up on the Housetop\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8de", "question": "In which hand is the Statue of Liberty holding a torch?", "answer": "Right hand", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1aa", "question": "What Elvis Presley film is set in England?", "answer": "Double Trouble", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e93a6f9d6f11f394a3b2d56", "question": "What is the Star Wars character Emperor Palpatine's first name?", "answer": "Sheev", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4ddf206d333868d34d70b", "question": "Which war was concluded by the Treaty of Utrecht?", "answer": "War Of Spanish Succession", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339165", "question": "What is the model name and number of the spacecraft's computer in \"2001: A Space Odyssey\"?", "answer": "HAL 9000", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a15c", "question": "The Silver Lion is awarded at which film festival?", "answer": "Venice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339038", "question": "Which music genre lilterally means \"new trend\" in Portuguese?", "answer": "Bossa Nova", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133893e", "question": "What armless statue in the Louvre is described as \"the most famous work of art of the ancient Greek sculpture\"?", "answer": "Venus de Milo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcda", "question": "What did Coleco name its 1983 home computer?", "answer": "Adam", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a528", "question": "Columbia University is located in which US city?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c44e", "question": "What are scientists hoping to cause when they seed a cloud?", "answer": "Rain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be6d", "question": "What was the Mellon Arena also known as?", "answer": "The Igloo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bff0", "question": "Where were fortune cookies invented?", "answer": "United States", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a076", "question": "In which TV series does Fred Savage play Kevin Arnold?", "answer": "The Wonder Years", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cfb", "question": "What is the dot on the letter i named?", "answer": "A tittle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339225", "question": "Who plays the role of Craig the puppeteer's wife in \"Being John Malkovich\"?", "answer": "Cameron Diaz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5dd", "question": "Brookline, Cambridge and Quincy are suburbs of what US city?", "answer": "Boston", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388b4", "question": "In Drop-D tuning, what is the lowest string of a guitar tuned down to?", "answer": "D", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a899b2560d398dc9cf7a69a", "question": "What type of animal is a Samoyed?", "answer": "Dog", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f1", "question": "What Agatha Christie novel was made up of two parts - England and Egypt?", "answer": "Death on the Nile", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391d7", "question": "Which famous BBC presenter goes by the name of Jezza?", "answer": "Jeremy Clarkson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a751", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Hawkeye State\"?", "answer": "Iowa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c689", "question": "What is the only vegetable that contains an alkaloid called capsaicin?", "answer": "Peppers", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393cc", "question": "In which James Bond movie does the character Pussy Galore appear in?", "answer": "Goldfinger", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a6dd20565ad31a57c7e0", "question": "Who was the founding commandant of the Nazi concentration camp Auschwitz?", "answer": "Rudolph H\u00f6ss", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4c0e49076251badbeacc", "question": "Who got married in the very first White House wedding?", "answer": "Dolley Madison\u2019s sister -- Lucy Payne Washington, the sister of First Lady Dolley Madison, married Thomas Todd in 1819.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2f0", "question": "What is the standard of strength of distilled alcoholic liquors called?", "answer": "Proof", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339404", "question": "What is the name of Nicole Kidman's character in the 2001 movie \"Moulin Rouge!\"?", "answer": "Satine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601de9f76b1208747aa7e9d5", "question": "In the Chinese zodiac, with which of the five elements is the snake associated?", "answer": "Fire -- It points to aggression and dominance.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc38", "question": "What was the motto of the 1972 Munich Olympic games?", "answer": "The Happy Games", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397a5", "question": "What city is home for TV's Golden Girls?", "answer": "Miami", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac76", "question": "Which invention resulted in the Printing Revolution across Europe?", "answer": "The printing press", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad9df04e748bb36357acde6", "question": "In speaking, the use of an incorrect word in place of a word with similar sound is known as what?", "answer": "A malaprop or Malapropism", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b93d", "question": "How many points are needed to win a game of handball?", "answer": "21", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6df", "question": "What flavor is Grand Marnier?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5cb70de5f96e155acab35d35", "question": "What two boxers fought in the famous match-up dubbed the \"Thrilla in Manila\"?", "answer": "Muhammad Ali and Joe Frazier", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1a2", "question": "What is Ozzy Osbourne's real first name?", "answer": "John", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ef", "question": "In the book \"Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows\" what does the acronym RAB stand for?", "answer": "Regulus A. Black", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b057", "question": "Who was Michael Dukakis\u2019s Vice-Presidential running mate in the 1988 US Presidential election?", "answer": "Lloyd Bentsen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe76a00eec85e375820b2b7", "question": "In what modern day country did the seven Churches of Asia once exist?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a28d", "question": "Who left Metallica to form Megadeth?", "answer": "Dave Mustaine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9a7", "question": "What mountain is the tallest point in Nepal?", "answer": "Everest", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a4e", "question": "What late 1970's hit contains the following line \"Ooh, you make my motor run, my motor run\"?", "answer": "My Sharona", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d06cda870e6f05ba600855", "question": "What is the capital of The Gambia?", "answer": "Banjul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcd8", "question": "What restaurant chain was the brainchild of Atari founder Nolan Bushnell?", "answer": "Chuck E. Cheese's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abfd", "question": "The Mus\u00e9e d'Orsay in Paris was originally what?", "answer": "Railway Station", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c620", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Carbon?", "answer": "C", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cae", "question": "Who wrote \"Tarzan of the Apes\" in 1912?", "answer": "Edgar Rice Burroughs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7ce23877e98cb97778a3c", "question": "Which country has Damascus as its capital city?", "answer": "Syria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aae5", "question": "In what country were Trabant cars made?", "answer": "East Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c20f", "question": "Which country hosted the first Winter Olympic Games?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c4b", "question": "What is the name of Captain Nemo's submarine in \"Twenty Thousand Leagues Under the Sea\"?", "answer": "The Nautilus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8f1cb01dd7bf43be5e808", "question": "Which Crayola color did consumers vote to save from retirement in 2003?", "answer": "Burnt sienna", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8b42601dd7bf43be5e7bc", "question": "What company was formerly named Cadabra Inc.?", "answer": "Amazon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5f1", "question": "The planet Uranus was originally named what?", "answer": "George's Star", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395ff", "question": "Which character does Kevin Spacey play in the 1995 movie \"The Usual Suspects\"?", "answer": "Roger Kint/Keyser Soze", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe937c36bd93ce3a4e5f676", "question": "Gamophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Marriage and commitment", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5902a0a9cad1ec93f27df76f", "question": "Who is credited with inventing the AeroPress?", "answer": "Alan Adler", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdfb8b8003d27d341092bc0", "question": "Where is the world's largest university by enrollment?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5901d967709c1c34536e6eab", "question": "What does sonography use to make pictures of the inside of the body?", "answer": "Sound waves", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5cd40cd3685cf15b733e9891", "question": "How many notes are there on a standard grand piano?", "answer": "88", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b014", "question": "The Orient Express is a train route between what two cities?", "answer": "Paris and Istanbul", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe12df1e39efa6330e0fed0", "question": "What is Europe's busiest cruise port?", "answer": "Barcelona, Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ff", "question": "What was Cape Kennedy renamed to in 1973?", "answer": "Cape Canaveral", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "597cd9a4e347d002c297e4cd", "question": "In modern badminton, how many points typically win a singles game?", "answer": "21", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396c4", "question": "Who directed the 2011 movie \"Red State\"?", "answer": "Kevin Smith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a1d", "question": "What M-word means the words at the bottom of a coat of arms?", "answer": "Motto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a939", "question": "What two colors are in the flag of Austria?", "answer": "Red and white", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6017375e44491cbd7c5a1789", "question": "Who designed and built the interior structure of the Statue of Liberty?", "answer": "The innovative designer and builder Gustave Eiffel and his structural engineer, Maurice Koechlin designed and built the statue.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c928", "question": "Approximately how many inches are in a meter?", "answer": "39", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff0b918e662d71a5365102c", "question": "\"The Color Purple\" begins, \"You better not tell nobody but\" who?", "answer": "God", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea77a2ff048f679a45abcb", "question": "What is another name for the vitamin B3?", "answer": "Niacin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5937eae708d98002fdd633a9", "question": "Whisky and Drambuie mix to form what cocktail?", "answer": "A Rusty Nail", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ae4", "question": "What 2001 Rachael Leigh Cook film was based on an old Saturday morning cartoon series?", "answer": "Josie and the Pussycats", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b61c", "question": "The fez originated from what country?", "answer": "Morocco", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c997", "question": "What colour bill does a Greylag goose have?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be3b", "question": "How many players are there in a standard polo team?", "answer": "Four", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5990af76b72eedf883a8c707", "question": "Which US state was nicknamed \"Old Dominion\"?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5977432a284458f1d7854427", "question": "Albert Einstein was offered the position of prime minister of what country?", "answer": "Israel", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e00", "question": "What is the Roman name of the Greek goddess Hestia?", "answer": "Vesta", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a490", "question": "What is the capital of Pakistan?", "answer": "Islamabad", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba1f", "question": "In golf, what is the traditional name for a number 3 wood?", "answer": "Spoon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d0662596a59cbdfbd37b", "question": "Who said, \"Whenever I hear anyone arguing for slavery, I feel a strong impulse to see it tried on him personally\"?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339591", "question": "What is outlawed in the town in the movie \"Footloose\"?", "answer": "Dancing and rock music", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eee", "question": "What woman's name has one \"L\" according to Elvis Costello but two according to the Pixies?", "answer": "Allison", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "596371ad967692ea851899bb", "question": "What country music singer was born in Muskogee, Oklahoma in 1983?", "answer": "Carrie Underwood", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be34", "question": "How many players are there in a standard volleyball team?", "answer": "Six", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b89", "question": "What film marked Julie Andrews first starring role?", "answer": "Mary Poppins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b45a", "question": "Who led over 900 followers in a mass suicide in 1978?", "answer": "Jim Jones", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4bb", "question": "Anthracite and bituminous are two types of what mineral?", "answer": "Coal", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcab", "question": "What four-letter clarified butter is commonly used in Indian cuisine?", "answer": "Ghee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9fb", "question": "Which natural phenomenon can be measured on the Mercalli scale?", "answer": "Earthquakes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe76840eec85e375820b29e", "question": "Which U.S. city is referred to as \"The Hub of the Universe\"?", "answer": "Boston, Massachusetts", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e2", "question": "What year was the first book of the \"Bourne Trilogy\" series first published?", "answer": "1980", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b279", "question": "What political party was led until 1985 by the brutal Pol Pot?", "answer": "The Khmer Rouge", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339549", "question": "What was the name of the dog on the TV show \"The Jetsons\"?", "answer": "Astro", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e74", "question": "Who played the blind character in the movie \"City Lights\"?", "answer": "Virginia Cherrill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c394", "question": "What is crossed with a blackberry and loganberry to produce a boysenberry?", "answer": "Raspberry", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ec2", "question": "In what Irish city did Frank McCourt set his memoir \"Angela's Ashes\"?", "answer": "Limerick", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e87", "question": "What future celebrity made an appearance as Opie in \"Andy Griffith\"?", "answer": "Ron Howard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ce8", "question": "What breed of dog is Marmaduke in the comic strip?", "answer": "Great Dane", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd08", "question": "What of the so-called original six teams was the NHL's first US franchise?", "answer": "The Boston Bruins", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ccf7a10b37b32637bdc44bf", "question": "What is it called when the liquid vapor pressure equals to the pressure of the gas above it?", "answer": "Boiling Point", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600cc1716de0eb824d4052df", "question": "What is the largest glacier in North America?", "answer": "Bering Glacier in Alaska holds the record as the largest glacier in North America.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133becf", "question": "What was the Paris stock exchange formerly known as?", "answer": "Paris Bourse", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59c1ceb97bd84c0ea43ad43b", "question": "Who is Thomas John Woodward better known as?", "answer": "Tom Jones", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b606", "question": "What American beer has been long promoted as the \"King of Beers\"?", "answer": "Budweiser", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eae", "question": "Who won Pulitzers for his plays \"A Delicate Balance\", \"Seascape\", and \"Three Tall Women\"?", "answer": "Edward Albee", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b37e", "question": "The Mason-Dixon line ran between Maryland and which other American State?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7c6", "question": "In what country is the holy city of Mecca?", "answer": "Saudi Arabia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd9c", "question": "What Kellogg's product was introduced to compete with Post's unsuccessful \"Country Squares\"?", "answer": "Pop-Tarts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6003988f57a0e35c43f8389c", "question": "What female surrealist did Andre Breton call \"the sorceress who left too soon\"?", "answer": "Male surrealists almost never saw female painters as capable artists.  Varo proved them wrong with her images of women.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8f32d01dd7bf43be5e815", "question": "What does SPF stand for?", "answer": "Sun Protection Factor", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398e5", "question": "What popular Motown group was originally known as \"The Primettes\"?", "answer": "The Supremes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbb7", "question": "What is the largest football stadium in Brazil?", "answer": "The Maracana stadium", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e9b6fe83fe1f2a824beb", "question": "Queen Mary Tudor of England is better known to history by what name?", "answer": "Bloody Mary", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad8e", "question": "Who introduced Christmas cookies to Canada in the 1700's?", "answer": "Germans", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f80", "question": "What was Robyn Hitchcock's backing band?", "answer": "The Egyptians", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339221", "question": "Which two artists formed the band \"Wham!\"?", "answer": "George Michael and Andrew Ridgeley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a38", "question": "What 1977 Paul Newman movie made cult stars of a trio of idiots named the Hanson Brothers?", "answer": "Slap Shot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f05", "question": "What TV series has produced episodes called \"...And Found\" and \"...In Translation\"?", "answer": "Lost", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c0a", "question": "What year did Anna Nicole Smith die from a drug overdose?", "answer": "2007", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0e8", "question": "What island nation was invaded by US troops in October 1983?", "answer": "Grenada", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e539fe83fe1f2a824bba", "question": "Which god is considered the \"destroyer\" and is part of the Hindu Trinity?", "answer": "Shiva", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aef9", "question": "What US president was nicknamed \"Honest Abe\"?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398e3", "question": "What \u201cStar Trek\u201d character had a name meaning \u201cfreedom\u201d in Swahili?", "answer": "Uhura", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e5f10d3d274615ecf514537", "question": "What is another name for the \"Battle of Greasy Grass\"?", "answer": "The Battle of the Little Bighorn", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59523d66736d4be723796b42", "question": "What is Canada\u2019s motto?", "answer": "From Sea to Sea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b23f", "question": "What royal subject married Rita Hayworth?", "answer": "Aly Khan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b679", "question": "Leather is the traditional gift for which wedding anniversary?", "answer": "Third", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6017373744491cbd7c5a1786", "question": "What is the name of the iron-clad ship that engaged the CSS Virginia during the American Civil War?", "answer": "On March 9, 1862, the CSS Virginia engaged the USS Monitor off Hampton Roads, Virginia in a naval battle that resulted in a draw.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d45", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"Anna and the King\"?", "answer": "Bai Ling", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a814", "question": "In what county is Chicago, Illinois located?", "answer": "Cook County", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339836", "question": "Who won a Grammy Award for her song \"Killing Me Softly\"?", "answer": "Roberta Flack", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ee", "question": "Which TV mom is a member of the \"Galaxy Women Historical Society\"?", "answer": "Jane Jetson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b37d", "question": "What was the first product to have a barcode?", "answer": "Wrigley's gum", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a17", "question": "Jamie Somers became \"The Bionic Woman\" following emergency surgery after what type of accident?", "answer": "Parachuting", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6012150063c99d48cd169ae5", "question": "Einstein won the 1921 Nobel Prize for Physics for explaining what?", "answer": "Photoelectric effect -- However, that did not stop him from giving a lecture\u00a0on relativity in his acceptance speech.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a9e95017ccba3ffe45786db", "question": "Which computer scientist was largely responsible for the design of \"FLOW-MATIC\", the first English-like data processing language?", "answer": "Grace Hopper", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397ac", "question": "What A-Team cast member was once a bodyguard for Muhammad Ali and Leon Spinks?", "answer": "Mr. T", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff145dbb0ee8c595b6d39bc", "question": "The pen name of which American writer means \"two fathoms deep\"?", "answer": "Mark Twain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b784", "question": "Who invented machine-spun cotton candy?", "answer": "William Morrison", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c852fbde8045e48466d6", "question": "When was the idea of the atom first introduced?", "answer": "Around\u00a0450 B.C. --  Leucippus and his pupil, Democritus, theorized that matter was composed bits of matter too small to be seen.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133985d", "question": "In the movie \"Nausicaa of the Valley of the Wind\", which actor portrayed Lord Yupa?", "answer": "Patrick Stewart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398be", "question": "What superhero's enemies include the Joker, the Penguin and the Riddler?", "answer": "Batman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecdb4dec223966ae8f88f2", "question": "In \"Ghostbusters,\" what prompts Dr. Peter Venkman to say, \"Well, there's something you don't see every day\"?", "answer": "Stay Puft Marshmallow Man", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396a5", "question": "The 1962 movie \"Lawrence of Arabia\" was based on the real-life exploits of whom?", "answer": "T.E. Lawrence", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59049aaecf93664eb1048699", "question": "Who was Joe\u2019s co-creator for the character of Superman?", "answer": "Jerry Siegel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1e1", "question": "What color was Tweety Bird originally?", "answer": "Pink", "category": "entertainment"}]